

PASS Engineer seeking roles in Software Configuration Management, Build Management, Release Management, Continuous Integration, Application Deployment, Agile Software Development, GIT, Ansible, Jenkins, Docker, Shell Script, Python, ANT, Maven, Kubernetes, Docker



Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: PASS Engineer -DevOps

Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions Inc. Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication] Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: PASS Engineer, Software Developer, Software Configuration Management, Build Management, Release

Management, Continuous Integration, Application Deployment, Agile Software

Development, GIT, Ansible, Jenkins, Docker, Shell Script, Python, ANT, Maven, Kubernetes, Docker

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

## Summary

7.4 years of experience in DevOps and Build and Release Engineer. Managing enterprise applications, version control tool administration and Application Deployment & Support.

Extensive experience in designing and implementation of CI/CD and DevOps processes for esteemed clients.

Experience with Agile software development.

Managing the Google Cloud infrastructure.

Creating the projects in Compute engine, resources allocations & load balancing.

Configuring Apache Zookeeper properties, consul configurations.

Administrating source code management using Git.

Maintained Jira for bug tracking and monitored consistently.

Created branches, Tags and handled merge activities using subversion and Git.

Experienced in implementing continuous integration using tools like Jenkins.

## Work Experience

#### Cognizant Technology Solutions Inc. as PASS Engineer -DevOps

May 2019 to Till Date

Title: PAAS Engineer Client: Kohl's Corporation

Tools/Environment: Docker, OpenShift, GCP, GIT, Jenkins, Prometheus, Grafana, Alert manager, Linux, JIRA,

kubernetes.

Duration: May 2019 - Present Role: PAAS L2 Engineer

#### Responsibilities:

Create OpenShift projects for the application teams.

Responsible for providing L2 support to the application teams w.r.t OpenShift environments.

Proficient with container systems like Docker and container orchestration Container Service, Kubernetes.

Used Kubernetes to orchestrate the deployment, scaling and management of Docker Containers.

Enhance the existing monitoring solution by creating dashboards in Grafana.

Create an alerting mechanism for different scenarios with in the OpenShift clusters.

Automate the repetitive tasks wherever required.

Continuously monitor the clusters for any unexpected behavior and provide the solution for the same using Prometheus. Work on the ad hoc requests from the dev teams through ServiceNow incidents.

#### GSPANN Technologies Inc. as DevOps Engineer

Apr 2016 to Apr 2019

Project #3

GSPANN Technologies, Inc. Hyderabad, India Project Title: E-Commerce Site (www.kohls.com)

Client: KOHL's Retail USA

Environment: ORACLE ATG E-Commerce, TONOMI, JIRA, Service- Now, VMware

Vcloud AIR, Java/J2EE, ANT, weblogic, Linux, Jenkins, Shell Scripting, Git, Maven, Jira and Nexus artifactory, micro

services ,google cloud platform GCP, kafka, zookeeper , Redis

Duration: April-2016 - April-2019

Designation: Software Engineer (NOC DevOps Engineer)

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

NOC support to ATG applications, various components involved like SKU search issues, Endpoint Configurations, Offers issue, Third party tool integrations like Skava, WCS, Fatwire, GIV, Taxware etc;

Managed the roles for Gerrit/ Jenkins/ Tonomi and Build engineer in this project.

Creating New Repository and branches in Gerrit.

Setting up the new build environment for various products in Linux environment in Vcloud Environment implemented the Release practice and responsible for pushing builds into DEV/ QA /Pre-Production environments.

Recommendation of SCM/Build/Release Process.

Involved in Deployment of the application using Weblogic/ Currently migrated to Micro Services.

Interacting with developers to sort out issues related to Build Automation.

Creating the Jenkins Jobs.

Maintaining Deployment guides for each release.

Implemented Containers for microservices in Test and UAT environments

Monitoring infrastructure with the help of dashboard and alerts

Uploading the artifacts in Nexus repository.

Managing/Tracking the defects status using Jira.

Involved in Jenkins Administrator, Service-Now.

Project involved the usage of maintaining repository and version controlling.

Continuous improvement of SCM process

Involved in Branching, Tagging of code delivery at required releases.

Co-work with the globally distributed Development team to fix the Build related issues.

Development of shell scripts for automation of existing manual processes.

Analyzing application logs in order to determine the possible cause of issues and reporting errors directly to the dev team.

Involved in Application support end to end and troubleshooting the issues reported by QA team.

Project #2: Meridian Bank, UK Role: Build & Release Engineer

Environment: GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Java, Red Hat Linux, Tomcat, Weblogic, Oracle and JIRA.

Roles and Responsibilities

Responsible for Build, Deployment of apps in to SIT, QA, UAT, PreProd and production environments.

Managing source code, change control, configuration management, build and deployment activities, and Setup Build & Release mechanism for new product lines.

Installed and maintained the GIT repositories.

Creation of GIT branches, merging branches, granting permissions to the users.

Locking branches, performing changes that are related to application configurations and pushing changes.

Managing and syncing up parallel applications/ releases in multiple environments. Implement automated build using Jenkins from scratch.

Responsible for the set up and ongoing maintenance of GIT

Promoting code from one Environment to another Environment.

Merging developer branches to Release/Integration branches.

Designed and implemented Continuous Integration process using tools like Jenkins with approval from development and other affected teams.

Package the binaries as per the requirement.

Manage Build and Release requests using Jenkins.

Configuration of Weblogic for different applications.

Responsible for the set up and ongoing builds in Jenkins.

Installing Plugins in Jenkins as per project requirements.

Involved in deploying WARs/EARs in to Weblogic Application Server using console and Scripts.

Starting, stopping, Restarting Servers and applications based on the user requests and to troubleshoot problems.

Creating the INC's, following up closely to bring the tickets to the closure with in SLA.

Modified Maven scripts to build the JAR's, WAR files and EAR files

GIT Maintenance of Maven, Shell scripts for safe builds and deploys.

### Cnetric Enterprise Solutions as Build & Release Engineer

Apr 2013 to Mar 2016

## **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2012

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
AWS, Google Cloud platform	
Git, Ansible	
Jenkins	
VMWARE	
DOCKER	
WINDOWS & Linux	
Shell Script, Python	
Ant, Maven	
NEXUS	
Apache Tomcat	
JBoss, Weblogic	
Oracle, MySQL, Mongo DB	
Apache Kafka, Rabbit MQ	
Apache Zookeeper	
Kubernetes, Docker	
Terraform	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time